Register of the Tibor Eckhardt papers
Hoover Institution Archives
- SUBJECT FILE, 1941-1972 (Boxes 5-24)
  - Assembly of Captive European Nations
    - 1956
    - 1958
    - 1959
    - 1960
    - 1962
    - 1964
  - Asylum, right of (Box 7)
  - Atlantic Council of the United States
  - Atlantic Partnership, Conference on the Concept of. American Institute of Problems of European Unity, Washington, D.C., 1969 October
  - Atom bomb
  - Auer, Paul (Pál)
  - Austria
  - Bachkai, Bela
  - Baker, Robert G.
  - Balassa, Bela
  - Baldwin, Hanson W.
  - Baltic states
  - Bandholtz, General Harry Hill
  - Bang-Jensen, Povl
  - Barankovics, Istvan
  - Barcza, Gyorgy
  - Bartok, Bela
  - Bartok, Laszlo, (2 folders)
  - Batori, Jozsef
  - Bazna, Elyesa
  - Beky, Bishop Zoltan
  - Belaunde Terry, Fernando
  - Beldy, Bela
  - Belgiumi Magyar Ifjusag (Hungarian Youth of Belgium), Leuven, Belgium, 1957 July
  - Belton, Rabbi Albert B.
  - Benes, Eduard
  - Benstead, Horace M.
  - Berlin crisis
    - 1959
    - 1961
  - Bess, Demaree
  - Bessenyey, Baron George B.
  - Bethlen, Count Istvan
    - "Bethlen Istvan eletenek utolso szakasza" (The last period of Istvan Bethlen's life), by Pal Bethlen
    - "Emlekirat a dunai foederacio targyaban" (Memorandum re a Danubian Federation), composed in Hungary in February 1944 and submitted to the British Government, carbon copy typescript in Hungarian and English translation
  - Bethlen Otton (Bethlen Home), Ligonier, Pennsylvania
  - Binder, David
  - Blacks
  - Bocskai, Prince Istvan of Transylvania
  - Bocskay von Felsobanya, Katalin
  - Boldizsar, Ivan
  - Bolles, Blair
  - Book reviews
  - Borsody, Istvan
  - Braziliai Magyar Segely Egylet (Brazilian Hungarian Relief Association)
  - Brezhnev, Leonid I.
  - Brezhnev Doctrine
  - Browne, Mallory
  - Buckley, William F., Jr.
  - Budapest, Hungary
  - "Budapesti level" (Letter from Budapest), Nemzetor, 1971 March
  - Bulganin Doctrine
  - Byng, Edward J.
  - Calasanctius Preparatory School, Buffalo, New York
  - Cameroon
  - Campbell, W. Glenn. "Campbell New Head of Hoover Library," clipping, 1959 November 19
  - Camus, Albert
  - Central and Eastern European Commission, Executive Committee Meeting, Paris, France, 1956 June 4 (Box 8)
  - Central Europe, blueprint for a neutralization of, 1972 February 16
  - Chamberlain, John
  - Chambers, Whittaker
  - Chiang Kai-shek
  - China
    - General
    - Armed Forces
    - Constitution
    - Description
    - Foreign relations
      - General
      - Russia
      - United States
      - Vietnam
    - History - Cultural Revolution
  - Chorin, Ferenc
  - Chou En-lai
  - Church and State - Hungary
  - Churchill, Winston, (2 folders)
  - Civil rights
  - Clevelandi Magyar Atletikai Club Unnepi Estelye (Hungarian Athletic Club of Cleveland)
  - Coalition of American Patriotic Societies
  - Colonialism
  - Columbus Forum
  - Commonwealth
  - Communism
  - Communists
  - Congo
  - Council for Liberation of Southern Hungary
  - Counterattack, 1968 May and July
  - Courts - United States
  - Crime and criminals - United States
  - Croatian Freedom Congress
  - Csaszari Konstantin Rend (Imperial Constantine Order)
  - Csavossy, Leo
  - Csizmadia, Zoltan
  - Csonka, Emil, (2 folders)
  - Cuba
  - Cultural relations
  - Czechoslovakia
  - Daladier, Edouard (Box 9)
  - Dalnoki-Veress, General Lajos
  - Deak, Ferenc
  - Debreceni magyar nyelvi konferencia (Hungarian Language Conference of Debrecen), Debrecen, Hungary, 1962 August 1-15
  - Delamerikai Magyarok Szovetsege (South American Hungarians' Federation)
  - Democracy
  - Deportation - Budapest, 1951 May
  - Djilas, Milovan
  - Dollar (U.S.)
  - Dominican Republic
  - Dunakurir (Danube Courier), 1950
  - Eckhardt, Ilka, 1926
  - Edelweiss (Anti-Nazi Movement)
  - Eden, Anthony
  - Education
    - General
    - Hungary
  - Eichmann, Adolf Otto
  - Eisenhower, Dwight D.
    - General (Box 10)
    - Visits abroad, 1959
  - Elections - Hungary, 1958
  - Eszterhas, Istvan
  - Eszterhazy, Count Janos
  - Ethics
  - Europai Magyar Felszabadito Bizottsag (European Hungarian Liberation Committee)
  - Europai Magyar Folelkeszek kozos nyilatkozata a Szentszek es a Magyar Kormany kozott letrejott megallapodassal kapcsolatosan (A concerted statement of the European Hungarian leading clergymen relating to the agreement between the Holy See and the Hungarian Government), 1964 September 16
  - Europai Parlament a magyar politikai foglyokert (The European Parliament for the Hungarian political prisoners), 1958
  - Europai Szabad Magyar Kongresszus (European Congress of Free Hungarians)
  - Europe
    - General
    - War
  - European Economic Community
  - "European Governments in Exile," compiled by Helen Lawrence Scanlon, Washington, D.C., Carnegie Endowment for International Peace, 1942
  - European security
  - Evelit, Juris
  - Fabian, Bela
  - Farkas, Laszlo
  - "A Feher Konyv szerint Amerika is osszeeskuvo" (According to the White Book America, too, is a conspirator), 1947
  - Fekete, Sandor
  - Feketekuty, Laszlo
  - "Felhaborito iteletek a szegedi szabadsagharcosok ugyeben" (Outrageous sentences in the case of the freedom fighters of Szeged), 1958
  - Fiala, Ferenc
  - First Slovak World Congress, New York, 1970 June 21
  - Fleming, Grace
  - Ford, Henry
  - Ford Foundation
  - Foreign aid - American
  - Fox, Robin
  - France
  - Franco, General Francisco
  - Free Europe, Inc.
  - Freedom and equality
  - Freemasons
  - Frey, Andras
  - Gabor, Aron
  - Gabriel, Asztrik
  - Galilei Kor
  - Gandhi, Mahatma
  - Gaulle, Charles de (Box 11)
  - Genscher, Hans Dietrich
  - Germany
    - General
    - Soviet-West German Treaty, 1970 August 12
  - Gettysburg Address
  - Ghana
  - Goebbels, Joseph
  - Goldwater, Barry
  - Great Britain
    - Foreign relations - China
    - Politics and government
  - Greece, The Federation of the Students' Board of
  - Guatemala
  - Guinea
  - Habsburg, Archduke Albrecht von
  - Habsburg, Archduke Felix von
  - Habsburg, Archduke Jozsef Arpad von
  - Habsburg, Archduke Otto von
    - General
    - Articles and essays
    - Books and pamphlets
    - Speeches
    - Interviews
    - Wedding
  - Habsburg, Archduke Robert von - Wedding
  - Habsburg, Archduke Rodolph von - Wedding
  - Habsburg, Archduchess Sarolta von - Wedding
  - Habsburg, House of - Genealogical table
  - Hahn, Otto
  - Haiti
  - Hamza, Andras
  - Hennyey, General Gusztav
    Detailed description of the political, military and general situation in Hungary during World War II.
  - Hertz, Frederick
  - Hess, Rudolph
  - Hevesy, Paul de
  - Himler, Marton
  - Hiss, Alger
  - Hitler, Adolph (Box 12)
  - Horthy de Nagybanya, Miklos
    Correspondence relating to the Regent's alleged plans to become King of Hungary.
  - Hosok Napi Emlekunnepely. Magyar Harcosok Bajtarsi Kozossege New Yorki Csoportja, (Commemorative Heroes Day. Fraternal Community of Hungarian Fighters, New York Group), clippings and correspondence, 1959
  - Humphrey, Hubert H.
  - Hungarian American National Republican Federation
  - The Hungarian Digest, Lancaster, Massachusetts
  - Hungarian Freedom Fighters' Federation, clippings, circulars and correspondence
  - Hungarian Institute at Rutgers University, New Jersey
  - Hungarian minorities
  - Hungarian-Nazi activities in the American zones of Germany and Austria, memorandum on
  - Hungarian newspapers
  - Hungarian poetry
  - Hungarian refugees
    - Austria
    - United States
  - Hungarian School Foundation, New York
  - Hungarian Students in North America, Association of
  - Hungarians in foreign countries
    - Canada
    - Chile
    - Romania
    - United States
    - Venezuela
    - Yugoslavia
  - Hungarians in the Free World
  - Hungarista Mozgalom (Hungarian movement)
  - Hungary
    - Allamvedelmi Hatosag (State Security Authority), clippings relating to the murder of Attila Kovacs, 1950
    - Economic conditions
    - Emigration and immigration
    - Foreign relations
      - Romania
      - Russia
      - United States
    - History
      - General
      - News and radio broadcasts during the last stage of World War II, 1944-1945
      - Soviet occupation, 1945-
      - Revolution, 1956; (10 folders)
    - Honvedseg
      - 2. Hadsereg. Don kanyari csata (A German General's letter commenting upon the Battle of the Don and the Hungarian 2nd Army), Munich, 1959 September 30
      - 9. hv. dd. pk. Torzsszallas (Report of Colonel Pisky describing the flight of the Romanians into Transylvania, pursued by the Soviet Army), 1944
    - Karpatalja (Carpatho-Ukrainia)
    - Kulugyminiszterium. Sajtoosztaly (Ministry of Foreign Affairs. Press section), 1944
    - Orszaggyules (Parliament)
      - Elections, 1947
      - Excerpts from the 203rd session of the Hungarian House of Representatives, 1937 April 28
    - Permanent Mission to the United Nations (Box 13)
    - Politics and government
      - 1918-1945, (2 folders)
      - Arrests, 1944
      - 1945-, (6 folders)
    - Population
  - I.R.O. - Italy, report about the Hungarian refugees in Italian refugee camps
  - Igazmondo (Truth Teller), N.Y., (some missing issues), 1941 August 25 - December 24
  - Ignotus, Paul (Pál)
  - Indonesia
  - Institute of Ethnic Studies, Georgetown University, Washington, D.C.
  - International Committee for the Study of European Questions
  - Iran
  - Ireland
  - Israel
  - Italy
  - Jambor, Louis
  - Jaszi, Oszkar
  - Jelic, Branimir R.
  - Jews
    - General
    - In Hungary
    - In Poland
  - Juvenile delinquency - United States
  - Kadar, Janos
  - Kallay, Miklos - Affidavit relating to the Jewish question in Hungary, 1952
  - Kanadai Magyarok Szovetsege (Canadian Hungarian Federation)
  - Kapotsy, Bela
  - Karoly, Peyer
  - Karoly IV
  - Karolyi, Count Mihaly
  - Karpatalja
  - Kashmir (Box 14)
  - Katanga
  - Kennedy, John F.
  - Kennedy, Robert F.
  - Kenya
  - Kenyatta, Yomo
  - Kerekes, Tibor
  - Kertesz, Stephen D.
  - Kethly, Anna
  - Khrushchev, Nikita S.
    - General
    - Visit to Hungary, 1958
    - Visit to the United States, 1959; (4 folders)
  - Khrushchev's Doctrine
  - Kiraly, General Bela
  - Kiss, George
  - Knights of Columbus
  - Kocsis, Gabor
  - Konkoly, Kalman
  - Korda, Geza
  - Korea, South
  - Korean War
    - Prisoners and prisons
    - Truman-McArthur controversy
  - Kosygin, Aleksey N. - Visit to Ottawa, Canada, 1971 (Box 15)
  - "Kossuth Lajos emlekezesei a lengyel forradalomrol..." (Reminiscences of Lajos Kossuth relating to the Polish revolution...)
  - Kovacs, Attila (murder victim, Austria, 1950)
  - Kovacs, Bela
  - Kovacs, Gyula
  - Koevago, Jozsef
  - Koezi-Horvath, Jozsef
  - Koezoes Magyar Kueluegyi Bizottsag (Common Hungarian Foreign Committee)
    - 1969
    - 1970
    - 1971
    - 1972
  - Kristol, Irving
  - Kun, Bela
  - Law and order
  - Lawrence, David
  - Lawyers - Budapest, Hungary
  - Lazar, Emry
  - Lekay, Laszo
  - Lenin, Vladimir Il'ich Ulianov
  - Leopold, King of Belgium - Surrender, 1940
  - Liang, Chi-chao
  - Lindsay, John
  - Liszay, Colonel
  - Lithuania
  - The Little Entente
  - Loden, Barbara
  - Lukacs, Gyorgy
  - Madariaga, Salvador de
  - Magyar Bizottsag (Hungarian Committee)
    - Membership list
    - Executive Committee - Plan of Work
    - Minutes of the July 14 session, 1948
    - Articles, correspondence, decisions, declarations, statistical data relating to Hungarians abroad in in the Free World, 1949
    - Articles, correspondence, minutes of sessions, reports, statements, statistical data relating to Hungarians abroad in the Free World, 1950
    - Refugee Service, Central Bureau, 1950
    - Correspondence, statements, clippings and bylaws of the Magyar Bizottsag, 1951
    - Articles, correspondence, "Deklaracio," minutes of sessions, speeches and clippings, 1952
    - Correspondence and statement: "Soviets Undermine Genocide Convention in the U.N.,", 1953 (Box 16)
    - Statement, 1955
    - Statement: Let us establish the Hungarian National Committee, 1956
    - Memoranda, questionnaire statements and clippings, 1957
    - Legal section: "Rejection of the Credentials of the Present Hungarian Delegation to the United Nations," by Laszlo Varga, 1958
    - Memorandum, 1959
    - The Hungarian issue and the international situation, 1963
    - The Hungarian Symposium, 1964
    - Statements, protests, correspondence, 1965
    - Statement, 1969
    - Statement in connection with Matyas Rakosi's death, 1971
    - Statement, 1972
  - Magyar Cserkesz Szoevetseg (Hungarian Scouts Association), 1970; (2 folders)
  - Magyar Demokratikus Szocialistak Szoevetsege (Hungarian Democratic Socialists' Association)
  - Magyar emigrans folyoiratok es koeroezvenyek (Hungarian emigrant periodicals and circulars), 1949-1968
  - Magyar Felszabadito Bizottsag (Hungarian Liberation Committee), 1970
  - Magyar Forradalmi Tanacs (Hungarian Revolutionary Council), 1957
  - Magyar Harcosok Bajtarsi Koezoessege (Hungarian Veterans' Federation), 1958-1959
  - Magyar Iskola Emlekkoenyve, 1960-1970. A New Brunswicki Hetvegi (Memorial Book, 1960-1970 of the New Brunswick Hungarian Week-end School), Rutgers University, New Jersey
  - Magyar iskolai tankonyvek (Hungarian schoolbooks), 1970-1971
  - Magyar iskolak emigracioban (Hungarian schools in emigration), 1970-1971
  - Magyar kerdes a jog merlegen (Legal aspects of the Hungarian question), 1963
  - Magyar Koezoesseg (Hungarian Community)
  - Magyar Koordinalo Bizottsag (Coordination Committee of American-Hungarian Organizations), 1971
  - Magyar Nemzeti Fueggetlensegi Front (Hungarian National Independence Front), no. 20, 1945 January-February
  - "A Magyar Nephadsereg" (The Hungarian People's Army), a description
  - Magyar Oktober 23 Mozgalom (Hungarian October 23 Movement, Inc.), 1964
  - "Magyar orientatio" (Hungarian orientation), a clipping, 1949
  - Magyar Parasztszoevetseg Emigracios Szervezete (Hungarian Peasant Federation's Organization in Emigration)
  - Magyar Piarista Diakszoevetseg (Hungarian Piarist Alumni Association), (3 folders)
  - Magyar politikai ueldoezoettek Vilagszoevetsege (World Federation of the Hungarian Persecuted) (Box 17)
  - Magyar Szabadsaghasrcos Szoevetseg (Hungarian Freedom Fighters Federation, Inc.)
    - Circular no. 21, 1965 January 8
    - American Chapter
      - 1969
      - 1970
      - 1971
      - Washington Chapter, 1972
  - Magyar Szabadsagharcos Vilagszoevetseg (World Federation of the Hungarian Freedom Fighters)
    - 1958
    - 1962
    - 1970
    - American Chapter
      - 1960
      - 1962
      - 1966
      - 1968
      - Periodic information
      - New York Chapter
  - Magyar Talalkozo (Hungarian Meeting), Ohio, Cleveland, 1970 November 29
  - Magyar Tanulmanyi Alap (Hungarian Scholarship Foundation), 1962
  - Magyar Toertenelmi Szemle (Hungarian Historical Review), 1970
  - Magyarok hazatereset eloesegito Bizottsag (Hungarian Repatriation Aid Committee), 1955
  - Magyarorszagi Hirek (News from Hungary)
  - Maisky, Ivan M.
  - Malnasi Oedoen. A magyar emigracio toertenete (The history of the Hungarian emigration)
  - Mao Tse-tung
  - Marcuse, Herbert
  - Marschlko, Lajos
  - Marshall, George C.
  - Mate, Imre
  - Meany, George
  - Mental illness - United States
  - Mikoyan, Anastas Ivanovich - Visit to the United States, 1959
  - Miksche, Ferdinand Otto
  - Mindszenty, Cardinal Joszef
  - Minorities - Czechoslovakia
  - Modern art
  - Molnar, Jozsef
  - Molnar, Miklos
  - Monarchy
  - Montgomery, John F.
  - Moral decay - United States
  - Moral rearmament
  - Morocco
  - Movement for the defense of the Hungarian nation in the United Nations
  - Munkas Hirado, 1959
  - Munnich, Ferenc
  - Nadanyi, Paul (Box 18)
  - Nagy, Ferenc
  - Nagy, Imre
  - National Resistance Party
  - Nemet-Szovjet Megegyezes (German-Soviet Agreement), 1970
  - Nepal
  - New Left
  - New York
  - News From Hungary, N.Y., 1955-1971
  - Nicolson, Harold
  - Nigeria
  - Nixon, Richard M.
    - General
    - "Khrushchev's Hidden Weakness"
    - Interview
    - U.S. Foreign Policy for the 1970s; Building for Peace
    - Visit to China
    - Visits to Moscow and Prague
  - North Atlantic Treaty Organization
  - Nuremberg Trial of Major German War Criminals, 1945-1946
  - Nyassaland
  - October 23, 1956 - Memorial meeting, N.Y., 1963
  - Onody, Desider de
  - Ordass, Lajos Bishop
  - Oszlanyi, Robert
  - Padanyi-Gulyas, Bela
  - Pakistan
  - Palestine-Arab delegation at the United Nations, N.Y.
  - Paloczi-Horvath, Gyorgy
  - Papp, Gyula
  - Pasztor, Laszlo
  - Peaceful coexistence
  - Peasantry
    - Eastern Europe
    - Hungary
  - Petofi Kor
  - Pfeiffer, Zoltan
  - Pogany, Andras
  - Poland
    - General
    - Treasures to be sent back by Quebeck
  - Pompidou, Georges
  - Powell, Paul
  - Prohaszka, Ottokar
  - Push, Ludovik
  - Radvanszky, Baron Antal (Box 19)
  - Rakosi, Matyas
  - Rattkay, R. Kalman
  - Religion
    - General
    - School prayer
  - Republican National Committee, Washington, D.C.
  - Republican National Committee, Nationalities Division, Hungarian Section, State of Illinois
  - Revay, Istvan
  - Revolution
  - Reynaud, Paul
  - Rhodesia
  - Ribbentrop-Molotov Pact, 1939
  - Romania - Politics and government
  - Roosevelt, Franklin D.
  - Russia
    - Communist party
    - Concentration camps - Maps
    - Foreign relations - China
    - K.G.B.
    - Naval power
    - Politics and government
      - General
      - Colonialism
      - Khrushchev removes Molotov and others
    - Soviet memorandum, Reply to, 1961 December 27
  - Salazar, Antonio de Oliveira (Box 20)
  - Sandor, Laszlo
  - Schell, Peter
  - Schwarz, Rudolf
  - Senegal
  - Sermon on the Mount
  - Sigray, Count Antal
  - Simonfay, Ferenc
  - Skadegard, Povl
  - Slovakia
  - Smith, Truman
  - Socialists
  - Sopron University in British Columbia
  - South Africa
  - Speer, Albert
  - Spies
    - Communist
    - Russian - Great Britain, 1971
    - West-German - West Germany
  - Sri Lanka
  - Stalin, Joseph
    - General
    - As Czarist spy
    - Reply to the Chief Correspondent of the British Reuters Agency, 1943 May 28
  - Stalingrad, Battle of, 1942-1943
  - Stimme der Freiheit, 1969 November-December, 1971 February
  - Strauss, Franz Josef
  - Sudan
  - Suicide - Hungary
  - Sulyok, Dezso
  - Sulzberger, Charles L.
  - Sun Tsu, the 13 points of
  - Suranyi-Unger, Theodor
  - Switzwerland - Army
  - Szabad Magyar Jogaszok Szovetsege (Federation of Free Hungarian Lawyers)
  - Szabad Magyar Mozgalom (Free Hungarian Movement)
    - Colorado Chapter
    - New York, N.Y., 1941 September 27
  - Szabad Magyar Szemle (Free Hungarian Review)
  - Szabad Magyarok Vilagszovetsege (World Federation of Free Hungarians)
  - Szabad Magyarorszag Nemzeti Kepviselete (National Representation of Free Hungary)
  - Szabadsagert Kuzdok Egyesulete (Union of Freedom Fighters)
  - Szabo, Miklos
    - General
    - Memorandum
  - Szalas, Sandor
  - Szamoskozi, Istvan
  - Szatmari, Jeno
  - Szechenyi, Count Charles
  - Szechenyi, Istvan - Dinners given in honor of
    - New York, 1955 December 2
    - 1971 November 20
  - Szechenyi Istvan Cserkesz Szabadegyetem (Stephen Szechenyi Boyscout Free University)
  - Szemle: Tudomanyos Irodalmi es Muveszeti Folyoirat (Szemle: A scientific literary and artistic journal)
  - Szent-Gyorgyi, Albert
  - Szent Istvan (St. Stephen's Day), 1952 August 20 and 1961
  - Szent Istvan Emlekbizottsag Anket (St. Stephen Conference of Commemorative Committee), 1970 January 24-25
  - Szent-Ivanyi, Sandor
  - Szent Korona (The Holy Crown)
  - Szeredas, Jeno (Box 21)
  - Slovak Vilagkongresszus (World Congress of Slovakians), 1971
  - Tabori, Gyorgy
  - Tartasdijegyezmeny (Nemzetkozi) es a Magyar Emigransok (The (International) Maintenance Fund and the Hungarian immigrants)
  - Teaching, freedom of
  - Teleki, Count Geza
  - Teleki, Count Pal
  - Terrorism
  - Thailand
  - Three-Power Conference, Moscow - Joint communiqué, 1945 December 16-26
  - Tibet
  - Tildy, Zoltan
  - Tisza, Count Istvan
  - Tito, Joseph
  - Tollas, Tibor
  - Transylvania
    - Erdely Vedelmeben Mozgalom (Movement in Defense of Transylvania) (Box 22)
    - Erdelyi Tajekoztato (The Transylvanian Informer)
    - Ethnographic Map of Hungary
    - Hungarians - Persecution of
    - O'Konskj, Alvin E. "The Historical Background of the Transylvanian Question," U.S. Congressional Record
    - Szent Ivanyi, Sandor. Vallasszabadsag Erdelyben Egykor es Most
  - Trials (Political crimes and offenses)
    - Hungary
    - Transylvania
  - Trianon, Peace Treaty of (June 4, 1920) - Commemoration
    - 1960
      - Butztown, Pennsylvania
      - New York City
    - 1970
      - General
      - Round Table Discussion
  - Trotsky, Leon
  - Truman, Harry S.
  - Tunisia
  - Turkey
  - Tyler, William R. - Statement, and the cause of captive nations
  - Ugron, Gabor
  - Uj Magyar Ut (The New Hungarian Way)
  - Ukrainian Congress Committee of America
  - United Nations
    - General
    - Membership - Admission of new members, 1955
    - Hungarian Revolution, 1956
    - General Assembly
      - 12th session, 1957
      - 13th session, 1958
    - 1962
    - 25th Anniversary session - Nixon's Address, 1970
  - United States
    - General (Box 23)
    - Declaration of Independence, July 4, 1776
    - Elections, 1968
    - Foreign policy (reappraisal)
    - Foreign relations
      - China
      - Great Britain
      - Hungary
      - Japan
      - Peru
      - Russia
        - General
        - Summit meeting, 1960
    - Policy mistakes
  - Vangel, Gyula
  - Varga, Bela
  - Varga, Laszlo
  - Vasvary, Odon
  - Vatican
  - Venezuela
  - Veres, Peter
  - Vietnam, South
  - Vietnamese Conflict
    - General
    - Mylai
  - Volt Politikai Foglyok Szovetsege (Federation of Former Political Prisoners)
  - Wallace, George
  - Warren, Earl
  - Warsaw Pact, 1955
  - Wass, Albert
  - William Penn Fraternal Association
  - Winnipeg Hungarian Literary Circle, 1961-1962
  - Wittfogel, Karl A.
  - Women's National Press Club (Box 24)
  - World politics, 1945-
  - World Radio University
    - General
    - Letters from France, nos. 1-12, 1940-1941
  - Yalta Conference, 1945
  - The Young Magyar-American, N.Y., 1938 July
  - Yugoslavia
  - Zelloy, Karoly
  - Zilahi, Lajos
  - Zionists
- PRINTED MATTER (Box 24)
  Miscellaneous clippings - Hungarian.
- SOUND RECORDINGS, 1952 (Box 24)
  Sound discs (45 rpm records in Hungarian) - Hungarian National Council.
  - 3 sound discs, 1952 September 18
  - 2 sound discs, 1952 October 1
  - 11 sound discs, 1952 October 2
  - 9 sound discs, 1952 October 10
  - 7 sound discs, 1952 October 15
  - 8 sound discs, 1952 October 28
  - 9 sound discs, 1952 November 25
  - 6 sound discs, 1952 November 26